<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <title>Country Loaf (Pain de Campagne) INGREDIENTS</title> 
    <ingredientList>
        <measurement n="1">1 1/4 cups</measurement>
        <measurement n="2">(160 grams)</measurement>
        <ingred>white bread flour</ingred>, plus more for dusting <measurement n="3">1/4 cup</measurement>
        <measurement n="4">(38 grams)</measurement>
        <ingred>stone-ground whole-wheat flour</ingred>
        <measurement n="5">1/4 cup</measurement>
        <measurement n="6">(32 grams)</measurement>
        <ingred>stone-ground whole rye flour</ingred>
        <measurement n="7">1/2 teaspoon</measurement> instant yeast<ingred/> or <ingred>bread machine
            yeast</ingred>
        <measurement n="8">1 teaspoon</measurement>
        <ingred>table salt</ingred>
        <measurement n="9">1/4 cup</measurement>
        <measurement n="10">(55 grams)</measurement> dry fermented cider (may substitute Pilsener beer; see
        headnote) <measurement n="11">1/2 cup</measurement>
        <measurement n="12">(120 grams)</measurement> lukewarm water 
        <measurement n="13">(80 degrees)</measurement>, plus an optional 
            <measurement n="14">1 tablespoon</measurement>
    </ingredientList> DIRECTIONS 
    <step n="1">Whisk together the <ingred>flours, yeast and
            salt</ingred> in a mixing bowl.</step>
    <step n="2">Combine the <ingred>cider and water</ingred> in a liquid measuring
            <measurement>cup</measurement>.</step>
    <step n="3">Add the liquid to the ;<ingred>flour mixture</ingred> use a spatula or bench scraper or
        your hand moistened with <ingred>water</ingred> to blend them for about a minute.</step>
    <step n="4">The dough should be shaggy yet cohesive. Cover the bowl with a towel; let the dough rest
        for <time>20 minutes.</time></step>
    <step n="5">Moisten your kneading hand.</step>
    <step n="6">If the dough seems stiff, add the optional <measurement>tablespoon</measurement> of
            <ingred>water</ingred>.</step>
    <step n="7">Stretch one edge of the dough (still in the bowl), then press it into the center of the
        bowl.</step>
    <step n="8">Repeat this about a dozen times, moving clockwise to catch all sides of the dough. (This
        should take 1 or 2 minutes.)</step>
    <step n="9">Turn the dough over so the seams are on the bottom. Cover and let rest for <time>20
            minutes.</time></step>
    <step n="10">Repeat the clockwise stretching and folding two more times, with <time>20-minute</time>
        rests after each.</step>
    <step n="11">Cover and refrigerate at least <time>8 hours</time> and up to <time>24 hours.</time> The
        dough should have doubled.</step>
    <step n="12">If it hasn't, leave it on the counter until it does.</step>
    <step n="14">Lightly flour a work surface.</step>
    <step n="14">Use a pastry cloth or clean dish towel to line a round colander. Dust the cloth with
        flour.</step>
    <step n="15">Transfer the dough to the floured work surface.</step>
    <step n="16">Fold the edges toward the center to create a round shape, turning it over so the seams are
        on the bottom.</step>
    <step n="17">Let it rest for <time>5 minutes,</time> then transfer to the colander, seam side
        up.</step>
    <step n="18">Cover with a towel and let the dough rise for <time>1 1/2 hours.</time></step>
    <step n="19">Thirty minutes before baking, place a cast-iron Dutch oven (lid on) or enameled cast-iron
        pot with a lid (on) in the oven; preheat to 475 <measurement>degrees.</measurement></step>
    <step n="20">Carefully remove the hot pot from the oven.</step>
    <step n="21">Turn the dough out onto the counter so the seams are on the bottom.</step>
    <step n="22">Use kitchen scissors to make 8 snips on the top of the dough in an evenly spaced spoke
        pattern, each about <measurement>1/4-inch</measurement> deep.</step>
    <step n="23">Lift the dough and carefully drop it into the hot pot.</step>
    <step n="24">Immediately cover with the hot lid.</step>
    <step n="25">Bake for <time>30 minutes,</time> then reduce the heat to 450
            <measurement>degrees.</measurement></step>
    <step n="26">Uncover and bake for <time>8 to 10 minutes</time> or until the crust is dark brown.</step>
    <step n="27">Try to minimize the amount of time the oven door is open.</step>
    <step n="28">The bread is done when its internal temperature registers 205
            <measurement>degrees</measurement> on an instant-read thermometer and the loaf sounds
        hollow when knocked on the underside.</step>
    <step n="29">Transfer the loaf to a wire rack to cool for at least <time>1 hour</time> before
        cutting.</step>
</root>
